<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Space Cowboy Coding</title><link>https://chrispyke.com/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Space Cowboy Coding</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 12:50:53 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chrispyke.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Brave New Virtual Worlds</title><link>https://chrispyke.com/post/brave-new-virtual-worlds/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 12:50:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chrispyke.com/post/brave-new-virtual-worlds/</guid><description>&lt;p>




&lt;img class="right corners" style="width:180px"
 srcset="
 /post/brave-new-virtual-worlds/headset_hu10990528044369252835.png 320w,
 /post/brave-new-virtual-worlds/headset_hu105074398216697766.png 600w,
 /post/brave-new-virtual-worlds/headset_hu16259931242636886721.png 1200w,
 /post/brave-new-virtual-worlds/headset_hu5201364261684643978.png 1500w"
 src="https://chrispyke.com/post/brave-new-virtual-worlds/headset_hu105074398216697766.png" alt="Virtual reality headset"/>


As technology progresses, so the world gets smaller. Virtual reality (VR) is allowing us to explore new worlds in new ways. It also has the potential to redefine how we interact virtually. It can close vase distances as participants play in the same virtual spaces.&lt;br>
&lt;br>
 Conversely, augmented reality (AR) is allowing us to layer more content on top of our own. This could change how we see our own world and everything that lives in it. Even though we have seen the potential for both of these technologies, mass adoption has still delayed the wave.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sweet Love Gateway</title><link>https://chrispyke.com/post/sweet-love-gateway/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 02:22:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chrispyke.com/post/sweet-love-gateway/</guid><description>&lt;p>




&lt;img class="right corners" style=""
 srcset="
 /post/sweet-love-gateway/night_1_hu16535715813921366524.jpg 320w,
 /post/sweet-love-gateway/night_1_hu8123731457106996148.jpg 600w,
 /post/sweet-love-gateway/night_1_hu5630843802002603111.jpg 1200w,
 /post/sweet-love-gateway/night_1_hu2969987058083199623.jpg 1500w"
 src="https://chrispyke.com/post/sweet-love-gateway/night_1_hu8123731457106996148.jpg" alt="The &amp;#39;Sweet love gateway&amp;#39; at night with red colour palette"/>


Ephemeropolis was my first burn. I got involved with the AfrikaBurn website build in 2010 but I never attended. It had long been on the to-do list, so we started making plans late 2018. The core build team included &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/igor.zeljko.77">Igor&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/alastair.mehl">Alastair&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/magoshashot">Margaret&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/tiffanychi101">Tiffany&lt;/a> and myself. Supporting the team was &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/CyBeRmAnZA">Bjorn&lt;/a> as well as the &amp;#39;NoFomosapiens&amp;#39;, who were all incredible. Oppikoppi and Meilie-pop had bigger build teams but many members couldn&amp;#39;t attend AfrikaBurn. Contributing to AfrikaBurn seemed natural since we had built structures at festivals before.&lt;br>
The project took the form of a &lt;a href="https://www.mathcurve.com/surfaces.gb/paraboloidhyperbolic/paraboloidhyperbolic.shtml">hyperbolic paraboloid&lt;/a> gateway (look at my fancy vocabulary). Igor, Alastair and Margaret had built this structure before at Oppikoppi. Based off of their insights, I thought there was room to refine &amp;#39;how&amp;#39; it was build. I also took on the responsibility of lighting the structure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Almighty Prototype</title><link>https://chrispyke.com/post/almighty-prototype/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 16:42:43 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chrispyke.com/post/almighty-prototype/</guid><description>&lt;p>





&lt;img class="right" style="width:130px;" src="https://chrispyke.com/post/almighty-prototype/prototype.svg" alt="Prototype graphic"/>


Hindsight is completely unforgiving. Looking back &amp;amp; observing oversights is a luxury most projects cannot afford. Allowing yourself space to fail &amp;amp; learn at an early stage of a project has advantages. It also allows a project to grow while preventing journey bottlenecks and minimising drop-offs.&lt;/p>
&lt;div id="outline-container-headline-1" class="outline-3">
&lt;h3 id="headline-1">
But I know what the user wants
&lt;/h3>
&lt;div id="outline-text-headline-1" class="outline-text-3">
&lt;p>Stakeholders or clients often do not see the true value of prototyping. Why budget time refining at the beginning of the project? But prototyping is not refining but rather narrowing the focus. The &amp;#39;agile approach&amp;#39; expects us to deploy a &amp;#39;minimum viable product&amp;#39; (MVP) as soon as possible &amp;amp; iterate on it. In the panic to get to market, it is easy to overlook the word &amp;#39;viable&amp;#39; in MVP.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ready, Set, React.</title><link>https://chrispyke.com/post/ready-set-react/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 16:42:43 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chrispyke.com/post/ready-set-react/</guid><description>&lt;p>





&lt;img class="right" style="width:180px;" src="https://chrispyke.com/post/ready-set-react/react.svg" alt="React logo"/>


I am surprised how quickly I took to &lt;a href="https://reactjs.org/">React&lt;/a>. I had completed &lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/3VS6JECTTJKS">Functional Programming in Scala&lt;/a> and was itching to apply the theory. I never anticipated how naturally React (and by extension functional programming) solved many of the problems I was facing. Below are some impressions of deploying my first React application.&lt;/p>
&lt;div id="outline-container-headline-1" class="outline-3">
&lt;h3 id="headline-1">
So it began
&lt;/h3>
&lt;div id="outline-text-headline-1" class="outline-text-3">
&lt;p>After doing some initial reading on &lt;a href="https://angularjs.org/">Angular&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://vuejs.org/">Vue&lt;/a>, I settled on React as it aligned closest to what I was trying to do. &lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/react-redux/">Modern React with Redux&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://www.udemy.com/webpack-2-the-complete-developers-guide/">Webpack 2: The Complete Developer&amp;#39;s Guide&lt;/a> provided a sufficient foundation to build upon. A team member who had developed in React before also provided some key insights.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Do you even functional bro?</title><link>https://chrispyke.com/post/do-you-even-functional-bro/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 15:45:43 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chrispyke.com/post/do-you-even-functional-bro/</guid><description>&lt;p>





&lt;img class="right" style="width:125px;" src="https://chrispyke.com/post/do-you-even-functional-bro/scala.svg" alt="Scala logo"/>


My interest grew from a side conversation I over-heard. After that, every taste taught me something different. There is something truly haunting about functional programming.&lt;br>
I have completed &lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/3VS6JECTTJKS">Functional Programming in Scala&lt;/a>. I was not fully prepared for the learning curve as many of the concepts and principles were new to me. What I took away from the course has had a real impact on the way I approach software development.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Joys of Craft</title><link>https://chrispyke.com/post/joys-of-craft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 07:37:40 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chrispyke.com/post/joys-of-craft/</guid><description>&lt;p>
I get great satisfaction from viewing a product I built using tools I prefer following principles I believe in. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>
On any given day, I work on a number of tech stacks that get the job done but leave me thinking, &amp;#34;If I could have built this from scratch?&amp;#34; Most projects suffer from budget &amp;amp; time constraints and end up being good enough. But when you do have enough time, when you are able to pick your tools and set them up just right and you watch them work together… then the endorphin&amp;#39;s flow. &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>We're Live!</title><link>https://chrispyke.com/post/we-are-live/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 13:49:02 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chrispyke.com/post/we-are-live/</guid><description>&lt;p>
This blog has been a long time coming. I have wanted to post on a number of things that completing the blog became a priority. Before I jump into topics of interest, I want to list some of the technologies driving the blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;div id="outline-container-headline-1" class="outline-3">
&lt;h3 id="headline-1">
Hugo
&lt;/h3>
&lt;div id="outline-text-headline-1" class="outline-text-3">
&lt;p>The more I use &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo&lt;/a>, the more I love it. My first attempts at a blog used database-driven content management systems (CMS), which made sense at the time. Database driven CMS&amp;#39;s are still relevant for large, distributed teams that need a central point to manage their content. The rise of &lt;a href="https://www.staticgen.com/">static site generators&lt;/a> allows us to sidestep the reliance on a back-end for simple sites. There is a static site generator suited for everyone but when Hugo started supporting &lt;a href="http://orgmode.org/">org-mode&lt;/a> for content was when I became hooked.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>